# **Sung Pil Moon**

# Curriculum Vitae

Department of Human-Computer Interaction School of Informatics Indiana University, Indianapolis 719 Indiana Avenue, Walker Plaza, Suite 360 Indianapolis, IN 46202 monspo1@gmail.com http://monspo1.github.io (317) 361 - 5563

### RESEARCH INTEREST

My research lies in Human-Computer Interaction (HCI), with primary interests in human behavior (e.g., motivation, behavior change and decision-making), usability and user experience, and interactive system design in conjunction with information visualization and persuasive elements. In particular, my current research interest focuses on creating useful and effective information visualization applications (both web and mobile)

- To provide users of the application more engaged and sustainable motivation to change their health behaviors
- To provide decision-ready visualized options for decision makers (including emergency responders, healthcare professional and patients) for more accurate and confident decision by reducing their cognitive burden in dynamic and uncertain situations and by interactively visualizing cause and effect relationships.
- To help aware of local health-related trends by showing meaningful and analytical visualized information extracted from social media data (e.g., Twitter, and Facebook)

### **EDUCATION**

# Ph.D. in Human-Computer Interaction School of Informatics, Indiana University, Indianapolis, IN • Dissertation title: Hamkerun: Mobile infoVis app towards sustainable motivation in a context of running. Master of Information Technology in eBusiness School of Computer Science, Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering Soongsil University, Seoul, Korea Republic May 2015 Aug. 2015 Feb. 2004

# **RESEARCH & PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

## **Graduate Research Assistant, Indiana University, Indianapolis**

<ul> <li>Patient empowerment with shared decision space project</li> <li>Develop a decision-making tool to enable both doctor and patient to attain shared decision space, deeper levels of option awareness and choose a robust option via information visualizations of the decision space.</li> <li>Funded by MITRE research Corporation (www.mitre.org)</li> <li>Project number: 51MSR605-BA and 51MSR603-AA</li> <li>Took a role for UI/UX design, data extraction and visualization, front-end development and usability testing</li> </ul>	Sep. 2012 – Aug. 2013
<ul> <li>GRAPPA decision space information development project</li> <li>Developed a decision space information visualization tool which is a model-based simulator to aid first emergency responder providing visualization of multiple decision options for more accurate and confident decisions.</li> <li>Funded by MITRE research Corporation (www.mitre.org)</li> <li>Project number: 43MSR001-EA, 45MSR026-FA</li> <li>Took a role for UI/UX design, front-end side development and usability</li> </ul>	Sep. 2008 – Mar. 2011
<ul> <li>Top Health Trends project</li> <li>Developed an information visualization tool showing local health-related Twitter trends to aid daily jobs of health-related experts.</li> <li>Collaborated with MESH coalition (www.meshcoalition.org)</li> <li>Took a main role in UI/UX design, front-end development, collecting requirements, and conducting usability tests</li> </ul>	Nov.2011 - June 2012
<ul> <li>ANRORA (Aural Navigation Flow On Rich website Architecture) project</li> <li>A NSF-funded project investigating linkless navigation strategy as a new way to increase mobile user experience while on-the-move.</li> <li>Developed an interactive mobile prototype (both in high fidelity and android version) and conducted usability tests.</li> </ul>	Sep.2012 – Jan. 2013
<ul> <li>MARVAND project</li> <li>Developed a mobile application supporting disaster relief activities for onsite volunteers after natural disaster.</li> <li>Took a main role in developing UI, front-end side, collecting user / system requirements, and conducting usability tests</li> </ul>	Nov.2012- Feb.2013
Teaching Assistant, Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh	Nov 2006
<ul> <li>Robot to the Rescue (RttR) class, Institute for Software Research (ISR)</li> <li>Led a course and offered a guidance of general introduction of robotics, and</li> </ul>	Nov.2006 – May 2008

developed a simulator with C#-based Microsoft Robotics Studio framework to communicate between mechanical devices and simulation services

### **PUBLICATIONS AND POSTERS**

### **Publications**

Moon, S. P. (2015). Hamkerun: Mobile infoVis app towards sustainable motivation in a context of running (Doctoral dissertation, Indiana University).

Moon, S. P., Liu, Y., Entezari, S., Pirzadeh, A., Pappas, A., & Pfaff, S. M. (May, 2013). Top Health Trends: An information visualization tool for awareness of local health trends. *10th International Conference on Information Systems for Crisis Response and Management (ISCRAM'13)*. Baden-Baden, Germany, May 12-15.

Pfaff, M. S., Klein, G. L., Drury, J. L., Moon, S. P., Liu, Y., & Entezari, S. O. (2012). Supporting complex decision making through option awareness. Journal of Cognitive Engineering and Decision Making, Advance online publication. doi: 10.1177/1555343412455799

Liu, Y., Moon, S. P., Pfaff, M. S., Drury, J. L., & Klein, G. L. (2011). Collaborative option awareness for emergency response decision making. Paper presented at the 8th Annual International Conference on Information Systems for Crisis Response and Management (ISCRAM), Lisbon, Portugal, May 2011.

Pfaff, M. S., Drury, J. L., Klein, G. L., More, L. D., Moon, S. P., & Liu, Y. (2010). Weighing decisions: Aiding emergency response decision making via option awareness. Proceedings of the 2010 IEEE International Conference on Technologies for Homeland Security (HST), 251-257.

### **Posters**

Moon, S. P., Liu, Y., and Powit, R. (2013, April). MARVAND: Mobile application for relief volunteering activity after natural disaster. Poster presented at the IUPUI Research Day 2013, Indianapolis, IN.

Bolchini, D., Rohani Ghahari, R., George-Palilonis, J., Moon, S.P., Archibald, C., & Kaser, L. (2012, November). Eyes-free web browsing with linkless navigation. IUPUI Innovation to Enterprise Showcase & Forum, IUPUI Campus Center, Indianapolis (IN), November 28, 2012.

Pfaff, M.S., Liu, Y., Moon, S. P., Entezari, S. O (2012, May). Effects of human-computer trust on collaborative decision making in a simulated emergency response. Poster presented at the 24th Annual Convention of the Association for Psychological Science, Chicago, IL. Pfaff, M.S., Moon, S. P., & Liu, Y. (2010, April). The GRaPPa lab: Supporting team decision making in complex environments. Poster presented at the IUPUI Research Day, Indianapolis, IN.

Luther, J., Moon, S. P., Davide, D., & Faiola, A. (2009, November). Advancing paper-in-screen prototyping: Evaluating and interacting with digital sketched designs. Presented at 2009 Indiana World Usability Day, Indianapolis, IN.

### **HONORS AND AWARDS**

Graduate Research Assistantship, Indiana University, Indianapolis	2008 - 2014
Scholarship for Talented Alumni Student from Soongsil University, Seoul, Korea	2012 - 2013
Scholarship for Talented Student, Ministry of Commerce, Industry and Energy of Korea	2005 – 2006

### HCI AND TECHNICAL SKILLS

### **Design Methods**

User-centered design, participatory design, ideation, affinity diagramming, scenarios, personas, information architecture, experience prototyping, technology probes

### User Research

Ethnography, contextual inquiry, focus group, experience sampling method, usability testing, heuristic analysis, GOMS, cognitive walkthrough, wizard of OZ, survey design & data analysis

### **Prototyping**

Sketching, low/mid/high fidelity prototyping, paper prototyping, experience prototyping, Flash, Photoshop, Balsamiq, Fluid UI

### Development

Java (SCJP; Sun Certified Java Programmer), Javascript, HTML5, CSS, XML, jQuery Mobile, C#, C/C++, Adobe Flex web / mobile programming, Actionscipt, Map SDKs (GoogleMap, MapQuest, ESRIMap), MySQL, Kinvey (BaaS), Bootstrap

### **PATENT**

### System and Method for Producing Video Map

Publication Number: US 8219912 B2, Published date: Jul 10, 2012